<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Meandering Out Loud]]></title>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T19:37:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://donthorp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Don Thorp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HowTo: Using a Magazine as a Media Player Stand]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/09/15/howto-using-a-magazine-as-a-media-player-stand/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-15T06:00:07-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/09/15/howto-using-a-magazine-as-a-media-player-stand</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/09/IMG_4461.JPG" alt="Using a magazine to hold your media player" title="Viewing Stand" style="margin-left:20px; margin-bottom:20px;" /></p>


<p>A magazine can be used to make an adhoc viewing stand for your media device. When I travel, flying mostly, I often want to watch movies or video podcasts during the trip. On one flight I was frustrated by having to hold the player so I tried to find something to rest the device on. </p>


<p>After failed attempts with various items from my travel bag, I decided I was ok with sacrificing an American Way magazine if it meant I could watch my content and banish hand cramps from my traveling experience.</p>


<p>After a couple of minutes experimentation, I developed the technique described below. <i>For those of you, like me, that are squeamish about bending pages, this technique is completely reversible causing no lasting damage to the magazine.</i></p>


<h4 style="clear:both">Materials</h4>


<ul>
<li>Magazine (Heavy covers work better</li>
<li>Media device (iPod Touch for me)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Steps</h4>


<ul>
<li>Orient the magazine so that the back is away from you.</li>
<li>Then lift the top 10-20 pages and fold the edge underneath into the back of the magazine.</li>
<li>Lift 15 pages or less and fold them up and into the back of the magazine.</li>
<li>Prop your device so that the back of the media player is against the first fold and the bottom is behind the second fold. Adjust the bottom fold as needed to prevent sliding</li>
</ul>


<h4>Video</h4>


<p>Here is a short video showing the technique.</p>


<p><p><object width="500" height="375"><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="movie" value="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=6592929&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=1&amp;show_byline=1&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1" /><embed src="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=6592929&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=1&amp;show_byline=1&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" width="500" height="375"></embed></object>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/6592929">HowTo: Create an iPod Stand from a Magazine</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/donthorp">Don Thorp</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve used this technique for many trips. It works well, there are always magazines in the seat back, and one less thing to carry.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Politicians, Manipulation, and the Healthcare Problem]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/08/15/politicians-manipulation-and-the-healthcare-problem/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-15T07:55:27-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/08/15/politicians-manipulation-and-the-healthcare-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In general, I&#8217;m not a big fan of politicians. I know they&#8217;re a necessary evil but I am troubled when they step over the line and over simplify and possibly just misstate facts just enough to inflame support for their position, whether their position is right/wrong, good/bad is immaterial.</p>


<p>What I&#8217;m not trying to do with this post is bash Obama, it is just an example of the type of speech that bothers me. Take a look at the two paragraphs below. This link was brought to my attention by <a href="http://twitter.com/repeatnone" target="_blank">@repeatnone</a>. I have included the link to the original letter, so please read it.</p>


<blockquote><p>
Yesterday during a town hall meeting, President Obama got his facts completely wrong. He stated that a surgeon gets paid $50,000 for a leg amputation when, in fact, Medicare pays a surgeon between $740 and $1,140 for a leg amputation. This payment also includes the evaluation of the patient on the day of the operation plus patient follow-up care that is provided for 90 days after the operation. Private insurers pay some variation of the Medicare reimbursement for this service.</p>
<p>Three weeks ago, the President suggested that a surgeon’s decision to remove a child’s tonsils is based on the desire to make a lot of money. That remark was ill-informed and dangerous, and we were dismayed by this characterization of the work surgeons do. Surgeons make decisions about recommending operations based on what’s right for the patient.<br />
- Excerpted from <a href="http://www.facs.org/news/obama081209.html">http://www.facs.org/news/obama081209.html</a>
</p></blockquote>


<p>Let&#8217;s examine the statement in the first paragraph. Anyone who has looked at an EOB (Estimate of Benefits, if you have insurance) knows that $50,000 does not go to one individual doctor and the amount that insurance reimburses the doctor is typically nowhere near the initial invoice amount. A portion goes to the hospital, the anesthesiologist, re-sterilizing instruments and the operating room, etc. It&#8217;s an over generalization that might lead someone not inclined to question blanket statements to take it as fact and spread the wrong message.</p>


<p>I have not read or seen the entire town hall transcript so I am definitely NOT trying to say it was deliberate. It could have been over simplified by an aide or later explained in full. I&#8217;m just trying to point out the danger in that type of statement. Although it&#8217;s for a smaller amount of money, the doctor asking to be paid amount X but agreeing to accept amount Y is no different than a grocery store asking you to pay X for canned goods, but will accept Y if you have a coupon. That part of the statement refers to a simple business transaction that many of use are very familiar with. It seems worse because the quoted invoice amount in absolute terms is so much more than a can of beans that it immediately invokes anger at the greed of the &#8220;doctor&#8221; to bill that amount.</p>


<p>Which brings us to paragraph two. Assigning intent to a group of people which implies that all members of that group have that exact motivation and can have no other motivation for the given statement. There are many ways this type of statement can be expressed. We all know that very few things in life have only two possible outcomes commonly described as black and white. Most everything in we actually deal with in life is probabilistic or shades of gray. Sometimes we only have horrible choices where we try and select the least horrible choice when we have to make a choice on the issue.</p>


<p>One of my favorite examples is when someone says &#8220;You always&#8221; or &#8220;You never&#8221;. Firstly, how many times is that ever true of anyone or any situation. Even trained dogs don&#8217;t always do the same thing. This statement usually appears during an argument when you want to inflict emotional damage to make a point. It&#8217;s hardly ever constructive.</p>


<p>To make a blanket statement that ascribes greed as the only motivation for a doctor to remove a child&#8217;s tonsils is no better than saying every American is just like George Bush, Bill Clinton, or insert any other person in the country here. We all know there are extremes where some members of a population may have that characteristic and we will probably admit, if we&#8217;re not being lazy, that there are many other people in that population that don&#8217;t exhibit that characteristic, in fact it&#8217;s probably a large portion of the population in question.</p>


<p>Finding a solution for healthcare in this country is a complex problem that by its very nature cannot be simplified to single one size fits all solution. I&#8217;m going to make some statements about why I believe this is true and I hope you&#8217;ll put together your own list and or help me extend or reduce mine.</p>


<p>1) As a nation we do not have unlimited resources to throw at this problem. We already have more programs than we can fund and we do not seem to have the collective will to cut any existing programs.</p>


<p>2) Doctors on average come out of school $100,000 in debt (<a href="http://www.studentdoc.com/medical-school-loans.html">http://www.studentdoc.com/medical-school-loans.html</a>). I did not look up the statistics for other healthcare providers, but I&#8217;m assuming that it&#8217;s non-zero. Do we really expect healthcare professionals to not be responsible and not pay off the debt or strive to achieve the American dream?</p>


<p>If you want best in the world medical care the people in that profession must have the ability to compete and gain personally from their efforts. How many of you would honestly say you&#8217;d be willing to have your pay capped indefinitely regardless of your expenses, abilities, and effort you put towards the task.</p>


<p>3) People expect doctors to be perfect in a profession that is not always predictable. Part of the existing problems we face is due to the litigious environment we have created. If any person is truly negligent or willfully deceives others then the full weight of the legal system should be brought against them. Another part of the problem can be ascribed to the medical profession, because they do not actively remove members that have demonstrated that they are incompetent. Another issue is the number of people who sue because they didn&#8217;t get the outcome they wanted. Things go wrong in biological systems that sometimes can&#8217;t be anticipated or corrected no matter the skill of the professional.</p>


<p>4) Many people don&#8217;t want to change their lifestyles to reduce their total medical burden. Many of the diseases that we currently face in this country can be attributed to lifestyle. People expect to be able to be sedentary, eat whatever they want, smoke, drink in excess and then have the best medical care in the world fix them when something in their body goes wrong due to that lifestyle. I believe deeply that people have the right to live how they want, but I also strongly believe that actions can have consequences and we can&#8217;t always be absolved from them at any price.</p>


<p>In closing, because I&#8217;ve expanding this post enough already. This problem is not going to be fixed by political grandstanding, fear mongering, and taking sides as if it were a sporting event. I think the number of people in this country that do not want to see everyone have access to quality health care is small and maybe even non existent. And if asked do you want your friends to have access to quality care and then extend that answer to those friends, pretty soon you&#8217;ll have covered everyone in the nation.</p>


<p>Take a stand against speech that tries to polarize or over simplify the problem into a sound byte. Act locally so it can spread nationally.  Acknowledge it for the complex problem that it is and then roll-up your sleeves and to try and help foster an environment where we can constructively build a system that we as a nation will be proud of that meets the needs of all of it&#8217;s citizens, including your elected officials.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scandinavia 09: DFW to HEL]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/08/06/scandinavia-09-dfw-to-hel/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-06T09:41:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/08/06/scandinavia-09-dfw-to-hel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Flights</h3>


<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/08/picture-4.png" alt="Flight from DFW to HEL" title="Flight from DFW to HEL" width="452" height="262" class="alignright size-full wp-image-431" />I seem to attract storms to DFW every time I fly in or out. Most of the day yesterday (Aug 5) was clear with not a cloud in sight. A few hours before I was suppose to leave, a storm front started moving into the metroplex. There was wind sheer near the airport and apparently 70 mph straight-line winds caused some damage in Grapevine. Thankfully is scooted just North of the Airport and my flight took off with just a short delay.</p>


<p>My first layover ended up being 10 minutes. Thankfully the flight got us to the gate early because it ended up being at least a half mile of hallways and rescanning through a security checkpoint from my landing gate to my departing gate. I flew from LHR (London) to (HEL) Helsinki via a code sharing British Airways flight. This was my first time on BA and it was pleasant as could be expected given that it was a 757 w/ 6 seats across. The staff was very friendly and although I didn&#8217;t take advantage of it, alcoholic beverages were complimentary. If I hadn&#8217;t wanted to reset my internal clock quickly (+8 hours) from home, I most certainly would have taken them up on the offer.</p>


<h3>Why are you in Finland</h3>


<p>Alex has been traveling all Summer in Europe. Laura and Allison traveled with him in July, but I had too many things to get done  and so I decided to travel with him in August. Another reason is that all I need is a net connection and power to work and so this is also a trip dedicated to working while living in different areas.</p>


<h3>Tomorrow - Aug 7</h3>


<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/08/picture-5.png" alt="Map of route from Helsinki to Rovaniemi" title="Map of route from Helsinki to Rovaniemi" width="309" height="380" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-434" />So the current plan is to head down to the train station in the morning and book a sleeper from Helsinki to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rovaniemi" target="_blank">Rovaniemi</a> where we will be staying at <a href="http://www.hotelsantaclaus.fi/?deptid=20899" target="_blank">The Clarion Hotel Santa Claus</a> for a couple of nights.</p>


<p>Then we&#8217;ll look around Helsinki until we need to board the train and see what the city has to offer near the train station. We will not be able to take advantage of much since we&#8217;re only here for about a day.</p>


<p> Since the nights are short I&#8217;m hoping to get a few photos during the train ride. We&#8217;re not sure what we&#8217;re going to do while we&#8217;re there, but it should be interesting.</p>


<h3>Oh, and the Hair</h3>


<p>So I had been warned by Allison and Laura that Alex&#8217;s hair was bleached blonde when they were traveling together. So naturally, as I exited the airport, I was looking for a tall kid with bleached blonde hair. At first I couldn&#8217;t figure out why this person with dark/black hair was headed up to me. Then I figured out it was Alex with blue hair so dark it looks like ink.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Titanium Android Development on Jaunty Jackalope]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/07/07/titanium-android-development-on-jaunty-jackalope/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-07T07:59:26-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/07/07/titanium-android-development-on-jaunty-jackalope</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/07/picture-91.png" alt="picture-9" title="picture-91" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-421" />I spent a good part of the morning looking for an answer to a support request: <a href="http://support.appcelerator.net/discussions/support/83-run-on-device-not-working" target="_blank">Run on Device Not Working</a>. The details are documented on the <a href="" target="_blank">Titanium documentation</a> site in <a href="http://www.codestrong.com/timobile/howto/develop-for-android-on-jaunty-jackalope/" target="_blank">HowTo: Develop for Android on Jaunty Jackalope</a>.</p>


<p><i>Update: I moved the instructions over to our documentation site where they&#8217;re easier to find.</i>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Twitter Decides We Have Enough Friends]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/twitter-decides-we-have-enough-followers/"/>
    <updated>2009-05-12T18:08:21-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/05/12/twitter-decides-we-have-enough-followers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/05/icon_a_down.png" alt="Tweeting Upside Down" title="icon_a_down" width="230" height="230" class="size-full wp-image-367" style="float:right; padding-right: 10px" />I don&#8217;t normally bother with posting about service changes, but <a href="http://twitter.com/" target="_blank">Twitter</a> has made a bone headed move in their latest service change: <a href="http://blog.twitter.com/2009/05/small-settings-update.html#links" target="_blank">Small Settings Update</a>.</p>


<p>A lot of experienced Twitter users <b>rely</b> on the one sided conversation feature to find <em>people worth following</em>. Seeing how people interact with others on twitter that I don&#8217;t already follow have resulted in some of my best online friends. Many of which I&#8217;ve met in real life.</p>


<p>So, Twitter, if you want to have the default setting be this new feature, then go ahead. But don&#8217;t take away one of the truly innovative features that have made the service what it is today. I&#8217;m not ready to stop discovering new interesting people, I want those one-sided replies. Otherwise, how am I suppose to expand my horizons and interact with people I&#8217;ve yet to meet.</p>


<div style="font-size: 130%; text-align: center">So <a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=%23fixreplies">#fixreplies</a>, please!</div>


<p><br/></p>


<blockquote style="font-size: 90%; background-color: #FFFFDD">
<h3>Post from Twitter</h3>
<h4><a href="http://blog.twitter.com/2009/05/small-settings-update.html#links" target="_blank">Small Settings Update</a></h4>
<p>We&#8217;ve updated the Notices section of Settings to better reflect how folks are using Twitter regarding replies. Based on usage patterns and feedback, we&#8217;ve learned most people want to see when someone they follow replies to another person they follow—it&#8217;s a good way to stay in the loop. However, receiving one-sided fragments via replies sent to folks you don&#8217;t follow in your timeline is undesirable. Today&#8217;s update removes this undesirable and confusing option.</p>
<p>
Confused? That&#8217;s understandable and exactly why we made the update.</p>
</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mistified]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/04/06/mistified/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-06T19:36:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/04/06/mistified</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/04/smist.png" alt="smist" title="smist" width="275" height="287" class="alignright size-full wp-image-349" /> A little travel tale for my trip to San Jose yesterday, April 6th. </p>


<p>On the Austin to San Jose leg, a guy who looked more sleep deprived than I felt, plopped down in the seat next to me with blanket in hand. He was quiet and immediately fell asleep. A bit later, as they were serving beverages, he woke up long enough to request a 7-up. The attendant handed him a can of Sierra Mist instead. Taking the cup and can, he took just enough time to fill the cup, drink half, then slipped back into a comatose state.</p>


<p>The flight was mostly smooth with the occasional moment of clear air turbulence. Each time we hit a rough patch, I&#8217;d glance over at his mostly full can and half-filled cup and wonder when they were going to end up all over me. </p>


<p>As we neared the end of the flight, my seat mate&#8217;s slumber took a slightly more violent turn. Every so often he&#8217;d suddenly shift and spasm which, more often than not, resulted in my being kicked or elbowed. It wasn&#8217;t pleasant, but it didn&#8217;t hurt so I let it be. Anyway, by this time, I was amazed that he never woke up and that the open containers of liquid were still perched on his tray ready to cover me in sticky goo in an upcoming spasm.</p>


<p>Apparently, the calm air and riveting podcast novel <a href="http://www.weatherchild.com" target="_blank">Weather Child</a> helped me forget about the drink. Very near the end of the flight, I was startled by the sound of his drink can hitting the tray and the cup, with some ice remaining, clattering off the side of the cabin and onto the floor.</p>


<p>Turning to see what had happened, I remember thinking, surely that will wake him up. Realizing that it wasn&#8217;t, I quickly reached over, righted the can, and then tried to wake him. I poked, prodded, and shook him and he slept right through it all. A little concerned I looked at his face and noticed that he was in REM sleep, dreaming away. Thinking on it now, I hoped it was at least a refreshing dream.</p>


<p>Not sure what else to do, I glanced over at the guy across the aisle and he shook his head, shrugged and offered no words of wisdom. Since I wasn&#8217;t his mother, I decided to just leave it alone. After having no luck trying to wake a man whose hand is sitting on the tray table in cold Sierra Mist while rivulets of lemon-lime water tumble over the side onto his already drenched pants, I decided to go back to my podcast.</p>


<p>A a couple of minutes later, just as I was about to push the attendant call button realizing there is still enough on the tray to drip on me if the plane banked right, he shifts in his seat and starts to wake. Half awake, it takes at least a couple of minutes for him to realize that he&#8217;s covered in sugar water and a couple more for him to reach up and press the call button to ask for napkins. Which by the way were the only words he spoke the entire flight.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto: Get More Tweets Per Hour in Tweetdeck]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/26/howto-get-more-tweets-per-hour-in-tweetdeck/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-26T15:52:11-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/26/howto-get-more-tweets-per-hour-in-tweetdeck</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/02/travelocity-nametag.jpg" alt="travelocity-nametag" title="travelocity-nametag" width="200" height="136" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-341" />I attended the <a href="http://twtvite.com/nfqdil" target="_blank">#dfwtweetup</a>, sponsored by Travelocity and Travel Studios, at <a href="http://www.awineexperience.com/default.aspx" target="_blank">Tastings</a> in Grapevine, TX this evening and had the good luck to learn a new hack. While sitting around talking about twitter search, <a href="http://blog.matthewjstevens.com/about/" target="_blank">Matthew J Stevens</a> aka <a href="http://twitter.com/GadgetVirtuoso">@GadgetVirtuoso</a> mentioned a technique he uses to effectively get more tweets per hour in <a href="http://www.tweetdeck.com/" target="_blank">Tweetdeck</a>.</p>


<p>The API Settings Window in Tweetdeck allows you to change the frequency of updates against three APIs: all friends, replies, and direct messages. The genius in his technique is that you can set up a search in Tweetdeck for your replies and it doesn&#8217;t count against your API limit.</p>


<p>I want to get all messages and direct messages delivered to Tweetdeck so I set my frequencies as shown in the image below. I like to leave a little slack, just in case I want to temporarily use another client, so I set the timings to use 90% of my API limit.</p>


<p>[caption id=&#8221;attachment_335&#8221; align=&#8221;aligncenter&#8221; width=&#8221;355&#8221; caption=&#8221;Tweetdeck Twitter API Settings&#8221;]<img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/02/picture-7.png" alt="Tweetdeck Twitter API Settings" title="Tweetdeck Twitter API Settings" width="355" height="366" class="size-full wp-image-335" />[/caption]</p>


<p>The second step is to create a search query for replies. I chose to only search on <a href="http://twitter.com/donthorp" target="_blank">@donthorp</a> mostly because I didn&#8217;t want to see my face in the column. To create this column, click on the search icon near the top (the magnifying glass) and then enter your twitter username in the search field. You can re-arrange your columns as you see fit. I chose to keep the <em>Replies</em> column and move it to the end and moved the new <em>@donthorp</em> column over where I had replies before.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Howto: Syncing TweetDeck Between Multiple Installs on OS X Using DropBox]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/21/howto-syncing-tweetdeck-between-multiple-installs-on-os-x-using-dropbox/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-21T10:43:47-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/21/howto-syncing-tweetdeck-between-multiple-installs-on-os-x-using-dropbox</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A big thanks to <a href="http://h0bbel.p0ggel.org/about" target="_blank">Christian Mohn aka h0bbel</a> for his <a href="http://h0bbel.p0ggel.org/howto-sync-settings-between-multiple-tweetdeck-installs-on-windows" target="_blank">article</a> on syncing TweetDeck between multiple Windows installations. It quickly pointed me in the right direction on OS X. In many ways, it&#8217;s much easier on OS X because it has soft links as part of its Unix heritage. Since I no longer use Windows computers for communication, I&#8217;ll leave it to someone else to figure out how to keep multiple OSs in sync.</p>


<h4>DropBox</h4>


<p>The technique I use also happens to take advantage of <a href="http://www.getdropbox.com/" target="_blank">DropBox</a>. If you&#8217;re not familiar with DropBox you should be. There are many ways to keep files in sync on multiple computers, some easier than others. I consider DropBox to be the easiest, most pain-free method I&#8217;ve found to date. DropBox provides a client integration piece that simply appears in your file system. Put a file in a folder and it will show up on all of your other machines.</p>


<p>DropBox also allows you to create shared folders for transferring files between friends and co-workers. <a href="http://www.johnmunsch.com">John</a> and I use it fairly regularly to transfer files that aren&#8217;t in our subversion repositories. I&#8217;ve also used DropBox to safely get files to and from my servers with their web interface. </p>


<h4>TweetDeck on OS X</h4>


<p>This howto assumes that you are already using TweetDeck on at least one computer. It should also be noted that this technique has the same limitation as h0bble&#8217;s; You must only run TweetDeck on one machine at a time. If this becomes an issue for me, I&#8217;ve considered creating a launcher for TweetDeck that would place a lock file in the shared directory to help prevent accidental launches. The same launcher could also monitor a termination file to close the remote instance.</p>


<p>TweetDeck stores your configuration files in your Preferences folder. As mentioned in h0bbel&#8217;s article, a random number is part of the filename. I used the Unix command <em>find</em> to locate my TweetDeck files. Open a terminal window in your home directory and issue the following command.</p>


<blockquote class="code"><p>
find . -name TweetDeckFast.*
</p></blockquote>


<p>You will most likely see multiple results. You are interested in the folder <em>Library/Preferences/TweetDeckFast.[random number]</em>. Inside that folder is a sub-folder named <em>Local Store</em> that TweetDeck uses to store your configuration files. There are two files of interest in that folder.</p>


<blockquote class="code"><p>
<em>preferences_[twitter_username].xml</em><br />
<em>td_26_[twitter_username].db</em>
</p></blockquote>


<h4>The Technique</h4>


<p>The technique takes advantage of the soft links I mentioned earlier. For those unfamiliar with the term, a soft link is simply a name or alias that provides a direct link to another name anywhere in the file system. Soft links will be created to fool TweetDeck into thinking its files are where they have always been, when in fact, they&#8217;re going to reside in the DropBox. DropBox will insure that the contents of the TweetDeck files are synchronized on all other computers where you have a DropBox as long as those machines have a network connection.</p>


<p>The reason it is important to run TweetDeck on only one machine at a time is that DropBox will try and keep the files in sync thereby generating conflicts in the files. The other reason is that you will blow through your Twitter API limits in no time.</p>


<h4>How</h4>


<ol>
<li>Stop TweetDeck on all computers</li>
<li>Open a Terminal window in your home directory</li>
<li>Create a folder in your DropBox.<br />
<blockquote class="code"><p>
mkdir Dropbox/TweetDeck
</p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>Change to your TweetDeck Local Store<br />
<blockquote class="code"><p>cd Library/Preferences/TweetDeckFast.*/Local\ Store</p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>Move your files to your DropBox<br />
<blockquote class="code"><p>
mv preferences*.xml ~/Dropbox/TweetDeck<br />
mv td_26_*.db ~/Dropbox/TweetDeck
</p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>Create your soft links. Please replace <em>[twitter_username]</em> with your twitter name. For example I used my twitter username <a href="http://twitter.com/donthorp" target="_blank">donthorp</a>.<br />
<blockquote class="code"><p>
ln -s /Users/$USER/Dropbox/TweetDeck/preferences_[twitter_username].xml&nbsp;preferences_[twitter_username].xml
</p></blockquote>
<blockquote class="code"><p>
ln -s /Users/$USER/Dropbox/TweetDeck/td_26_[twitter_username].db&nbsp; td_26_[twitter_username].db
</p></blockquote>
</li>
</ol>


<p>On every other machine you want to use your synchronized TweetDeck files do the following</p>


<ol>
<li>Stop TweetDeck</li>
<li>Open a Terminal window in your home directory</li>
<li>Verify that DropBox has synchronized your TweetDeck files. You should see the .xml and .db files.<br />
<blockquote class="code"><p>
ls Dropbox/TweetDeck
</p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>Change to your TweetDeck Local Store<br />
<blockquote class="code"><p>cd Library/Preferences/TweetDeckFast.*/Local\ Store</p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>Remove your files so that you can create your symlink. Note: If you want to preserve them, copy them somewhere else before deleting.<br />
<blockquote class="code"><p>
rm preferences*.xml<br />
rm td_26_*.db
</p></blockquote>
</li>
<li>Create your soft links. Please replace <em>[twitter_username]</em> with your twitter name. For example I used my twitter username <a href="http://twitter.com/donthorp" target="_blank">donthorp</a>.<br />
<blockquote class="code"><p>
ln -s /Users/$USER/Dropbox/TweetDeck/preferences_[twitter_username].xml preferences_[twitter username].xml
</p></blockquote>
<blockquote class="code"><p>
ln -d /Users/$USER/Dropbox/TweetDeck/td_26_[twitter_username].db td_26_[twitter_username].db
</p></blockquote>
</li>
</ol>


<p>Now you are ready to enjoy TweetDeck with all of your setting synchronized between machines. While I used DropBox for this solution, it is not required. Any method you have of moving the actual TweetDeck files between machines will suffice. Personally, using DropBox made it simple, efficient, and took advantage of my current workflow.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dell to Expand Recycling Efforts]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/11/dell-to-expand-recycling-efforts/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-11T09:14:16-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/11/dell-to-expand-recycling-efforts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dell is expanding its recycling efforts by adding six additional states to its drop off at GoodWill program and an online exchange program. <a href="http://www.reconnectpartnership.com/">Reconnectpartnership.com</a> has a list of dropoff locations.</p>


<p>More information is available in <a href="http://gristmill.grist.org/story/2009/2/11/9485/96824" target="_blank">Dell to Pay</a> a post by <a href="http://gristmill.grist.org/user/Jonathan%20Hiskes">Jonathan Hiskes</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Audiobook: The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/02/free-audiobook-the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-02T07:04:34-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/02/free-audiobook-the-7-habits-of-highly-effective-people</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?t=donthorp-20&o=1&p=8&l=as1&asins=0743269519&md=10FE9736YVPPT7A0FBG2&fc1=000000&IS2=1&lt1=_blank&m=amazon&lc1=0000FF&bc1=000000&bg1=FFFFFF&f=ifr" style="width:120px;height:240px; float:right; padding-left: 10px;" scrolling="no" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" frameborder="0"></iframe>As a long time Audible listener, I&#8217;m always looking to add new books to my library. Occasionally, Audible has a promotion and gives away a free book to existing members as well as non-members. While catching up on <a href="http://twit.tv/twit">This Week In Tech</a> podcasts, I heard that <a href="http://audible.com" target="_blank">Audible.com</a> in conjunction with <a href="http://twit.tv" target="_blank">TWIT.tv</a> is giving away <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steven_R._Covey">Steven R. Covey&#8217;s</a> <a href="http://bit.ly/3kb3dM" target="_blank">The 7 Habits of Highly Effective People</a>.</p>


<p><a href="http://bit.ly/3kb3dM" target="_blank">Download for FREE</a>. </p>


<p>This offer is valid for non-members and current members. I believe I heard Leo say the offer expires February 15th. </p>


<p>If you&#8217;re not into audiobooks I&#8217;ve provided a link to the book on Amazon where you can order it in print form. Click on the &#8220;Buy from Amazon.com&#8221; button and order it today.</p>


<div style="clear:both;">&nbsp;</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Food: Piggies in and on a Blanket]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/01/food-piggies-in-and-on-a-blanket/"/>
    <updated>2009-02-01T08:56:31-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/02/01/food-piggies-in-and-on-a-blanket</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/02/img_1979-version-2-200x150.jpg" alt="Piggie in a Blanket" title="img_1979-version-2-200x150" width="200" height="150" class="size-full wp-image-301" style="float:left; padding-right: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px"/> Today I attempted to make piggies in a blanket. The recipe is simple.</p>


<blockquote><p>
1 or more tubes of biscuits<br />
1 little smokie per biscuit<br />
Use cooking times and temperature from biscuit packaging.</p>
<p>Lightly grease a cookie sheet. Using one sausage per biscuit, wrap the smokie snuggly with a biscuit and place on the cookie sheet.
</p></blockquote>


<p>Apparently, I failed the &#8220;wrap smokie snuggly&#8221; part on some of the &#8220;Piggies in a Blanket&#8221; and ended up with new recipe which I&#8217;ve called &#8220;Piggies In and On a Blanket&#8221;. Next time I will try wetting the edge of the biscuit so that it stays together, or roll the biscuit until it appears seamless.</p>


<p>Close ups.</p>


<p>[gallery columns=&#8221;3&#8221; orderby=&#8221;post_name&#8221;]</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Projects: Bedroom Remodel]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/20/projects-bedroom-remodel/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-20T17:49:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/20/projects-bedroom-remodel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/gallery/7149761_axaYq" class="noicon" target="_blank" style="float: right; padding-left:10px; padding-bottom: 10px;"><img src="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/photos/458754492_kbWud-S.jpg" border="no"/></a> I&#8217;ve create a <a href="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/gallery/7149761_axaYq" target="_blank">gallery</a> of photos from the remodel of Allison&#8217;s bedroom. She wanted her walls red with a dark wood floor. Given the experience we had with renovating my office in 2008, we were confident we could crank out most of the work over the MLK holiday weekend. As of this post we&#8217;ve completed everything except the baseboard and moving her in.</p>


<p>We ripped out the 13+ year old carpet and replaced it with a floating bamboo floor. The walls were painted with a dark brown (Behr Bison Brown) and then covered the brown with red (Behr Daredevil). The eggshell finish for the red gives it a glazed look and provides for an interesting finish over the brown. The original baseboard was repainted and replaced and shoe molding will be added to cover any gaps from contraction.</p>


<p>I hope to post a howto in the future, now that we&#8217;ve installed two floating floors using this bamboo flooring, </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Banking: The Positive Pay System]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/08/banking-the-positive-pay-system/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-08T10:28:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/08/banking-the-positive-pay-system</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/01/banking.gif" alt="banking" title="banking" width="79" height="49" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-228" />I learned something new today about a system called &#8220;Positive Pay&#8221; that&#8217;s used in the banking system. It&#8217;s one of those systems that you just wouldn&#8217;t notice until something went wrong. </p>


<p>Earlier today, I tried depositing a check from a company only to have the the teller inform me that it couldn&#8217;t be deposited today. When I asked why, she told me it was due to the fact that it wasn&#8217;t in the system. Once I got home and looked up the number for the company, I called them, explained the situation, and they simply retransmitted the check details. </p>


<p>Since I helped build an ACH processing solution, I was curious about what this system entailed. Descriptions from several locations appeared using this <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=positive+pay" target="_blank">Google search</a>. One of the better descriptions was from <a href="http://www.positivepay.net/index.htm" target="_blank">SafeChecks</a>. Here is an excerpt.</p>


<blockquote><p>
Positive Pay is an automated fraud detection tool offered by the Cash Management Department of most banks. In its simplest form, it is a service that matches the <b>account number</b>, <b>check number</b> and <b>dollar</b> amount of each check presented for payment against a list of checks previously authorized and issued by the company. All three components of the check must match exactly or it will not pay.
</p></blockquote>


<p>The purpose of this system is to help prevent check fraud and the simplicity of it is encouraging. I can only hope that during transmittal they take the time to digitally sign the transactions.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Photos Page and WP-SmugMug]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/07/new-photos-page-and-wp-smugmug/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-07T18:56:55-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/07/new-photos-page-and-wp-smugmug</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of my site re-organization and update, I discovered a new plugin, <a href="http://www.tow.com/projects/wordpress/wp-smugmug/" target="_blank">WP-SmugMug</a> written by <a href="http://www.tow.com/about/" target="_blank">Adam Tow</a>, that allows me to show recent photos from my SmugMug account on the site. Previously, the <b>Photos</b> menu item just took you directly to my photos, <a href="http://photos.donthorp.net" target="_blank">http://photos.donthorp.net</a>, on SmugMug. Now the link takes you to a local page that displays some recent photos and provides a link to all photos.</p>


<p>I had a couple of small issues with the plugin, version 2.0.3 and WordPress 2.7, but that didn&#8217;t stop me from working around it for photos.</p>


<ol>
<li>The &#8220;Send to Editor&#8221; button didn&#8217;t work for me so I had to enter the short code by hand (FireFox 3.0 and Safari on OS X Leopard)</li>
<li>When using the RSS feed for recently updated galleries, it didn&#8217;t find the gallery images to display so I took that feature out.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updated to Wordpress 2.7]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/04/updated-to-wordpress-27/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-04T13:43:27-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/04/updated-to-wordpress-27</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a just a quick post to note that I&#8217;ve finished porting the site to Wordpress 2.7 and taking it into production. I haven&#8217;t made any of the organizational changes that I want yet, but now that it&#8217;s moved I may post some of the content that I&#8217;ve been saving up a lot faster.</p>


<p>If you notice anything wrong with the site, please leave a comment on this post.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[T-Mobile G1: Accidental Wallpaper]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/12/04/t-mobile-g1-accidental-wallpaper/"/>
    <updated>2008-12-04T07:10:01-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/12/04/t-mobile-g1-accidental-wallpaper</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really like my <a href="http://www.t-mobileg1.com/" target="_blank">G1</a>, but I&#8217;m not really happy with the camera. It&#8217;s slow to focus and takes forever to actually snap a picture. I did discover, during the writing of this post, that the camera button is actually a two stage button: Press part way and wait for the green focus light, then press all the way to capture. This technique speeds up the actual photo capture. But it is still slow. I&#8217;m hoping that the speed is a software issue that can be fixed with a patch rather than a hardware limitation of the device. That said, this slowness can actually be beneficial in producing artistic effects.</p>


<p>We were out at dinner last night in a reasonably lit restaurant and I tried to snap a photo of Allison sitting across the table. She did her normal hide from the camera move and I ended up with an image that turned out to be great for use as wallpaper on the device. </p>


<p><img src="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/photos/430228331_vMEZk-S.jpg" /></p>


<p>The <a href="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/gallery/6736031_hUcsj/1/#430228331_vMEZk-A-LB" target="_blank">image</a> is available for personal use. A screen capture of my phone with the wallpaper is below. When setting the wallpaper, Android let&#8217;s you choose a portion of the image. </p>


<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/12/wallpaper.png" alt="G1 Screen Capture" title="Screen capture of wallpaper on my G1" width="320" height="480" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-128" /></p>


<p>It turns out that it is not possible to perform on-device screen captures at this time, but it can be done using the DDMS tool that comes with the Android sdk. Reference links are provided below.</p>


<h3>Reference Links</h3>


<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.mobilecrunch.com/2008/10/31/how-to-capture-the-screen-of-an-android-device/" target="_blank">How-to: Capture the screen of an Android device</a></li>
<li><a href="http://code.google.com/android/reference/ddms.html" target="_blank">Using the Dalvik Debug Monitor Service (DDMS) Tool</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thoughts for All Voters - My Only Political Post of '08]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/11/04/thoughts-for-all-voters-my-only-political-post-of-08/"/>
    <updated>2008-11-04T04:39:19-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/11/04/thoughts-for-all-voters-my-only-political-post-of-08</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A friend sent me this collection of quotes before he headed to the polls. </p>


<h3>Thoughts about Obama and Democrats</h3>


<blockquote style="background-color: #EEEECC"><p>
A government which robs Peter to pay Paul can always depend on the support of Paul.<br />
- George Bernard Shaw
</p></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>
A liberal is someone who feels a great debt to his fellow man, which debt he proposes to pay off with your money.<br />
-G Gordon Liddy
</p></blockquote>


<blockquote style="background-color: #EEEECC"><p>
A government big enough to give you everything you want, is strong enough to take everything you have.<br />
-Thomas Jefferson
</p></blockquote>


<h3>Thoughts about McCain and Republicans</h3>


<blockquote style="background-color: #EEEECC"><p>
Giving money and power to government is like giving whiskey and car keys to teenage boys.<br />
-P.J. O’Rourke, Civil Libertarian
</p></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>
Government’s view of the economy could be summed up in a few short phrases: If it moves, tax it. If it keeps moving, regulate it. And if it stops moving, subsidize it.<br />
-Ronald Reagan (1986)
</p></blockquote>


<blockquote style="background-color: #EEEECC"><p>
The ultimate result of shielding men from the effects of folly is to fill the world with fools.<br />
-Herbert Spencer, English Philosopher (1820-1903)
</p></blockquote>


<h3>Thoughts FOR Libertarians</h3>


<blockquote style="background-color: #EEEECC"><p>
There is no distinctly Native American criminal class…save Congress.<br />
-Mark Twain
</p></blockquote>


<blockquote><p>
What this country needs are more unemployed politicians.<br />
-Edward Langley, Artist (1928 - 1995)
</p></blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Impression: T-Mobile G1]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/10/23/first-impression-t-mobile-g1/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-23T17:30:54-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/10/23/first-impression-t-mobile-g1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had several people ask for my impressions of the G1 so I put a video together instead of spending a lot of time typing. In general, it&#8217;s pretty good for a first generation device. I don&#8217;t really like the bar with the roller obstructing access to the keyboard, but I&#8217;m starting to get use to it already. </p>


<p><object width="320" height="240"><param name="allowfullscreen" value="true" /><param name="allowscriptaccess" value="always" /><param name="movie" value="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=2052291&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=1&amp;show_byline=1&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1" /><embed src="http://vimeo.com/moogaloop.swf?clip_id=2052291&amp;server=vimeo.com&amp;show_title=1&amp;show_byline=1&amp;show_portrait=0&amp;color=00ADEF&amp;fullscreen=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="always" width="320" height="240"></embed></object><br /><a href="http://vimeo.com/2052291?pg=embed&amp;sec=2052291">First Impressions: T-Mobile G1</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/user867450?pg=embed&amp;sec=2052291">Don Thorp</a> on <a href="http://vimeo.com?pg=embed&amp;sec=2052291">Vimeo</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meme: Six Random Facts About Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/10/21/meme-six-random-facts-about-me/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-21T16:44:44-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/10/21/meme-six-random-facts-about-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So my Twitter bud <a href="http://babblingaboutnothing.com/" target="_blank">Matt</a> aka <a href="http://twitter.com/mmWine" target="_blank">mmWine</a>, using his best evil laugh, <a href="http://babblingaboutnothing.com/?p=83" target="_blank">meme tagged</a> me for &#8220;Six Random Facts About Me&#8221;. Looking around the Net I see that this meme has been running around for a while and has stayed basically true to form. The main deviation is changing the number of <b>random facts</b>. Since I wanted to be able to get some sleep tonight, I&#8217;m very thankful that Matt is passing on the six facts meme and not the 8 facts meme.</p>


<h2>Random Facts</h2>


<p>Let&#8217;s consult &#8220;The Book of Don&#8221;. </p>


<h3>Random Fact #1</h3>


<p>As a kid, I usually minded pretty well, but in this case I &#8220;bent&#8221; the rules a bit. We lived on a ranch in Missouri that had several ponds. One day as I was heading out for some reason mom told me to not get wet. Not sure how she knew I was considering going swimming in the pond, but she must have had an idea. But, I really wanted to see what it was like to swim in early April after the ice had thawed. Solution: Skinny dippin and  for the record it was cold, not too bad, but it also gave me the ability to sympathize with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Costanza" target="_blank">George Constanza</a> years later. Oh and I returned home safe and dry.</p>


<h3>Random Fact #2</h3>


<p>Growing up on a ranch you also need certain skills, one of which is artificially breeding cattle. It&#8217;s one of those skills that I don&#8217;t think one can ever forget.</p>


<h3>Random Fact #3</h3>


<p>Laura and I got engaged after our third date. She lived in Amarillo at the time and I was still going to school at TCU. She had graduated a little earlier from TCU. Neither of us knew the other while we were at TCU. So three dates in less than a month and we&#8217;re engaged. I can still remember us telling her parents as we were putting up the Christmas tree. First words out of her father&#8217;s mouth &#8230; &#8220;Are you pregnant&#8221;. </p>


<p>It&#8217;s worked out pretty well, we just had our 21st anniversary.</p>


<h3>Random Fact #4</h3>


<p>I&#8217;ve worked on many different projects over the years but three consumer items that I worked on were.</p>


<ol>
<li><a href="http://store.vintagepaperads.com/servlet/-strse-8908/1993-Tandy-Sensation-Computer/Detail" target="_blank">Tandy Sensation</a> the first Windows multimedia PC. Some one even put up a video of an <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h3U7DFUqoVM&feature=related" target="_blank">old commercial</a></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tandy_Video_Information_System" target="_blank">Tandy VIS</a> a horribly flawed device that we actually made sort of work, but it failed miserably.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/126692-3/the_25_greatest_pcs_of_all_time.html" target="_blank">Gateway Destination PC</a> item #20 towards the bottom of the page. First real attempt to have a converged device in the Den.
</ol>


<h3>Random Fact #5</h3>


<p>I&#8217;ve been growing my hair out for over 18 months. The story of which will appear in an upcoming blog post. In the spirit of baring oneself, most of the hair is on the sides and back; Not so much contributed from the top of my scalp.</p>


<h3>Random Fact #6</h3>


<p>Self-funded (read really similar to starving college days) Select Payment Processing, with some friends. It was successfully sold years later.</p>


<h2>Tag You&#8217;re It</h2>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/jmthorp" target="_blank">@jmthorp</a> who is my brother and writes <a href="http://thorplife.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">http://thorplife.wordpress.com/</a> after the kids crashed the hard drive on his old site.</p>


<p>John Munsch who has no twitter account, a long time friend,  and writes <a href="http://www.johnmunsch.com/" target="_blank">http://www.johnmunsch.com/</a></p>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/frizzle_fry" target="_blank">@frizzle_fry</a> Melissa Astle <del datetime="2008-10-22T19:53:58+00:00">who also has no twitter account,</del> whom I&#8217;ve worked with for years, never met, and writes <a href="http://randommisfires.wordpress.com" target="_blank">http://randommisfires.wordpress.com</a></p>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/dogwood" target="_blank">@dogwood</a> who writes <a href="http://thedogwoodreport.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">http://thedogwoodreport.blogspot.com/</a></p>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/stevesaylor" target="_blank">@stevesaylor</a> who writes <a href="http://stevesaylor.net/" target="_blank">http://stevesaylor.net/</a></p>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/pprlisa" target="_blank">@pprlisa</a> who never writes but should at <a href="http://lemloo.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">http://lemloo.wordpress.com/</a></p>


<h2>The Rules</h2>


<p>The rules to play are easy …<br />
1. Link to the person who tagged you. <a href="http://babblingaboutnothing.com/?p=83" target="_blank">Matt Tagged me here</a>.<br />
2. Post the rules on the blog.<br />
3. Write six random things about yourself.<br />
4. Tag six people at the end of your post.<br />
5. Let each person know they have been tagged.<br />
6. Let the tagger know when your entry is up.</p>


<p>I look forward to learning about y’all. Tag, you’re it!</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Your Bacon Is in My Pumpkin]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/10/18/people-you-have-a-pumpkin-and-bacon-problem/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-18T08:57:13-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/10/18/people-you-have-a-pumpkin-and-bacon-problem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="float:right; margin-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 5px;"><object width="213" height="172"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/ZfbTO0GlONU&hl=en&fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/ZfbTO0GlONU&hl=en&fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" width="213" height="172"></embed></object></div>


<p>For months I&#8217;ve had a nagging suspicion and you&#8217;ve probably noticed it too: we&#8217;re in the midst of a bacon and pumpkin epidemic. It&#8217;s not hard to miss given bacon&#8217;s dalliances in <a href="http://www.browniepointsblog.com/2008/01/20/homemade-bacon-vodka/" target="_blank">bacon infused vodka</a>, <a href="http://www.davidlebovitz.com/archives/2008/03/candied_bacon_i_1.html" target="_blank">candied bacon ice cream</a>, and the true heart stopper &#8211; <a href="http://www.dallasnews.com/sharedcontent/dws/fea/taste/stories/090208dnmetfriedfoods.33839923.html" target="_blank">chicken fried bacon</a>. Pumpkin is no homebody either; out there galavanting around in <a href="http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Pumpkin-Chocolate-Chip-Muffins/Detail.aspx" target="_blank">pumpkin chocolate chip muffins</a>, <a href="http://www.foodnetwork.com/recipes/wolfgang-puck/pumpkin-ravioli-recipe/index.html" target="_blank">pumpkin ravioli, and <a href="http://www.cooks.com/rec/view/0,196,134186-243195,00.html" target="_blank">pumpkin jelly rolls</a>. I&#8217;m all for culinary experimentation, but this is a plague of mutated foods that threatens us all.</p>


<div style="float:left; margin-right: 10px; margin-bottom: 5px"><object width="213" height="172"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/JWMM7HPeTHQ&hl=en&fs=1"></param><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"></param><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/JWMM7HPeTHQ&hl=en&fs=1" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" width="213" height="172"></embed></object></div>


<p>Look back to the somewhat provocative Reese&#8217;s  <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Reese_Peanut_Butter_Cups#Marketing_and_advertising" target="_blank">marketing campaign</a> of the 1970s and 1980s where we learned that some things, like chocolate and peanut butter, do belong together. This campaign helped bring about a new world order where people were free to co-mingle ingredients in an understanding environment. Nowhere in the campaign did they suggest there was a license for wholesale promiscuity between all editable items. </p>


<p>I LUV bacon and adore pumpkin; but seriously, some things are not meant to be joined. I&#8217;m not trying to discourage experimentation and creativity as I want new culinary delights just like the next guy.  Experiment if you dare, but post warnings when it goes wrong, don&#8217;t propagate the misfortune by turning it into a recipe and publishing it world-wide. That recipe might appear in some demented marketing company&#8217;s campaign: &#8220;AS SEEN ON THE INTERNET, foods to torture your tastebuds and upset your stomach&#8221;. It&#8217;s just not right.</p>


<p>Interventions are a common method of helping people confront their problem. Earlier this week <a href="http://www.cbs.com" target="_blank">CBS&#8217;s</a> &#8221;<a href="http://www.cbs.com/primetime/how_i_met_your_mother/" target="_blank">How I Met Your Mother</a>&#8221; had an <a href="http://www.cbs.com/primetime/how_i_met_your_mother/video/video.php?cid=446409135&pid=GFNexppkA_nOChnF0tUyNF3TjCEVQceU&category=editorial&play=true" target="_blank">episode</a> in which the group staged interventions at the drop of a hat. While they almost needed an intervention for interventions, I&#8217;m a little disappointed that they didn&#8217;t recognize the need for a bacon and pumpkin intervention.  Consult the table of Google search results or hop on over to <a href="http://search.twitter.com" target="_blank">twitter search</a> and you&#8217;ll be amazed at how often these items appear. We&#8217;re clearly out of control. While I was typing the last 2 sentences, the <i>bacon OR pumpkin</i> search had 6 updates.</p>


<table style="left-margin: 50px">
<tr>
<td style="padding-right: 20px;">
<table style="background-color: #EEEEEE">
<tr style="background-color: #E0E0E0">
<th>Google Search</th>
<th>Result Count</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&q=recipe&btnG=Search" target="_blank">recipe</a></td>
<td align="right">102,000,000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&q=bacon&btnG=Search" target="_blank">bacon</a></td>
<td align="right">46,000,000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&q=pumpkin&btnG=Search" target="_blank">pumpkin</a></td>
<td align="right">34,000,000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&q=%2Brecipe+%2Bpumpkin&btnG=Search" target="_blank">pumpkin+recipe</a></td>
<td align="right">3,600,000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&q=%2Brecipe+%2Bbacon&btnG=Search" target="_blank">bacon+recipe</a></td>
<td align="right">375,000</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&q=%2Brecipe+%2Bbacon+%2Bpumpkin&btnG=Search" target="_blank">bacon+pumpkin+recipe</a></td>
<td align="right">247,000</td>
</tr>
</table>
<td style="padding-left: 20px" valign="top">
<table style="background-color: #EEEEEE">
<tr style="background-color: #E0E0E0">
<th>Twitter Search</th>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=+bacon" target="_blank">bacon</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=+pumpkin" target="_blank">pumpkin</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=&ands=bacon+pumpkin&phrase=&ors=&nots=&tag=&lang=all&from=&to=&ref=&near=&within=15&units=mi&since=&until=&rpp=15" target="_blank">bacon pumpkin</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://search.twitter.com/search?q=&ands=&phrase=&ors=bacon+pumpkin&nots=&tag=&lang=all&from=&to=&ref=&near=&within=15&units=mi&since=&until=&rpp=15" target="_blank">bacon OR pumpkin</a></td>
</tr>
</table>
</td>
</tr>
</table>


<p><br/></p>


<p>Did you noticed that there were <b>247,000</b> results for recipes that combine bacon and pumpkin; it&#8217;s just not holy. Every year I look forward to Fall and the return of the venerable pumpkin pie. Be creative if you must, alter the spice proportions, change sweeteners, or adjust the flakiness of the crust, but don&#8217;t follow Joe and codify desecration of a sacred food. Imagine my horror when I discovered this abomination, <a href="http://allrecipes.com/Recipe/Joes-Incredible-Bacon-Pumpkin-Pie/Detail.aspx" target="_blank">&#8220;Joe&#8217;s Incredible Bacon Pumpkin Pie&#8221;</a>. This could be the tip of the iceberg, what&#8217;s next; bacon soda?</p>


<p>Don&#8217;t just sit there when it&#8217;s clear we have a problem. Call your friends. Alert the neighbors. Then let&#8217;s gather at Joe&#8217;s for the first of many interventions.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
