<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Travel | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T18:27:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://donthorp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scandinavia 09: DFW to HEL]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/08/06/scandinavia-09-dfw-to-hel/"/>
    <updated>2009-08-06T09:41:22-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/08/06/scandinavia-09-dfw-to-hel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Flights</h3>


<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/08/picture-4.png" alt="Flight from DFW to HEL" title="Flight from DFW to HEL" width="452" height="262" class="alignright size-full wp-image-431" />I seem to attract storms to DFW every time I fly in or out. Most of the day yesterday (Aug 5) was clear with not a cloud in sight. A few hours before I was suppose to leave, a storm front started moving into the metroplex. There was wind sheer near the airport and apparently 70 mph straight-line winds caused some damage in Grapevine. Thankfully is scooted just North of the Airport and my flight took off with just a short delay.</p>


<p>My first layover ended up being 10 minutes. Thankfully the flight got us to the gate early because it ended up being at least a half mile of hallways and rescanning through a security checkpoint from my landing gate to my departing gate. I flew from LHR (London) to (HEL) Helsinki via a code sharing British Airways flight. This was my first time on BA and it was pleasant as could be expected given that it was a 757 w/ 6 seats across. The staff was very friendly and although I didn't take advantage of it, alcoholic beverages were complimentary. If I hadn't wanted to reset my internal clock quickly (+8 hours) from home, I most certainly would have taken them up on the offer.</p>


<h3>Why are you in Finland</h3>


<p>Alex has been traveling all Summer in Europe. Laura and Allison traveled with him in July, but I had too many things to get done  and so I decided to travel with him in August. Another reason is that all I need is a net connection and power to work and so this is also a trip dedicated to working while living in different areas.</p>


<h3>Tomorrow - Aug 7</h3>


<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/08/picture-5.png" alt="Map of route from Helsinki to Rovaniemi" title="Map of route from Helsinki to Rovaniemi" width="309" height="380" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-434" />So the current plan is to head down to the train station in the morning and book a sleeper from Helsinki to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rovaniemi" target="_blank">Rovaniemi</a> where we will be staying at <a href="http://www.hotelsantaclaus.fi/?deptid=20899" target="_blank">The Clarion Hotel Santa Claus</a> for a couple of nights.</p>


<p>Then we'll look around Helsinki until we need to board the train and see what the city has to offer near the train station. We will not be able to take advantage of much since we're only here for about a day.</p>


<p> Since the nights are short I'm hoping to get a few photos during the train ride. We're not sure what we're going to do while we're there, but it should be interesting.</p>


<h3>Oh, and the Hair</h3>


<p>So I had been warned by Allison and Laura that Alex's hair was bleached blonde when they were traveling together. So naturally, as I exited the airport, I was looking for a tall kid with bleached blonde hair. At first I couldn't figure out why this person with dark/black hair was headed up to me. Then I figured out it was Alex with blue hair so dark it looks like ink.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mistified]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/04/06/mistified/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-06T19:36:24-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/04/06/mistified</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/04/smist.png" alt="smist" title="smist" width="275" height="287" class="alignright size-full wp-image-349" /> A little travel tale for my trip to San Jose yesterday, April 6th. </p>


<p>On the Austin to San Jose leg, a guy who looked more sleep deprived than I felt, plopped down in the seat next to me with blanket in hand. He was quiet and immediately fell asleep. A bit later, as they were serving beverages, he woke up long enough to request a 7-up. The attendant handed him a can of Sierra Mist instead. Taking the cup and can, he took just enough time to fill the cup, drink half, then slipped back into a comatose state.</p>


<p>The flight was mostly smooth with the occasional moment of clear air turbulence. Each time we hit a rough patch, I'd glance over at his mostly full can and half-filled cup and wonder when they were going to end up all over me. </p>


<p>As we neared the end of the flight, my seat mate's slumber took a slightly more violent turn. Every so often he'd suddenly shift and spasm which, more often than not, resulted in my being kicked or elbowed. It wasn't pleasant, but it didn't hurt so I let it be. Anyway, by this time, I was amazed that he never woke up and that the open containers of liquid were still perched on his tray ready to cover me in sticky goo in an upcoming spasm.</p>


<p>Apparently, the calm air and riveting podcast novel <a href="http://www.weatherchild.com" target="_blank">Weather Child</a> helped me forget about the drink. Very near the end of the flight, I was startled by the sound of his drink can hitting the tray and the cup, with some ice remaining, clattering off the side of the cabin and onto the floor.</p>


<p>Turning to see what had happened, I remember thinking, surely that will wake him up. Realizing that it wasn't, I quickly reached over, righted the can, and then tried to wake him. I poked, prodded, and shook him and he slept right through it all. A little concerned I looked at his face and noticed that he was in REM sleep, dreaming away. Thinking on it now, I hoped it was at least a refreshing dream.</p>


<p>Not sure what else to do, I glanced over at the guy across the aisle and he shook his head, shrugged and offered no words of wisdom. Since I wasn't his mother, I decided to just leave it alone. After having no luck trying to wake a man whose hand is sitting on the tray table in cold Sierra Mist while rivulets of lemon-lime water tumble over the side onto his already drenched pants, I decided to go back to my podcast.</p>


<p>A a couple of minutes later, just as I was about to push the attendant call button realizing there is still enough on the tray to drip on me if the plane banked right, he shifts in his seat and starts to wake. Half awake, it takes at least a couple of minutes for him to realize that he's covered in sugar water and a couple more for him to reach up and press the call button to ask for napkins. Which by the way were the only words he spoke the entire flight.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Trip to Mexico - Tulum]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2002/07/16/trip-to-mexico-tulum/"/>
    <updated>2002-07-16T16:57:55-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2002/07/16/trip-to-mexico-tulum</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>
We recently returned from a trip to Mexico and I've started organizing the pictures from the trip.<br />
Since that will take a while, I decided to post  some panorama's of the ruins of Tulum.  Click on<br />
the smaller images to see a larger version.</p>


<p>
<wpg2>4097|400</wpg2><br />
<wpg2>4101|400</wpg2><br />
<wpg2>4104|400</wpg2></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
