<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Banking | Meandering Out Loud]]></title>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/categories/banking/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T18:57:07-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://donthorp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Don Thorp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Banking: The Positive Pay System]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/08/banking-the-positive-pay-system/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-08T10:28:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/08/banking-the-positive-pay-system</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2009/01/banking.gif" alt="banking" title="banking" width="79" height="49" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-228" />I learned something new today about a system called "Positive Pay" that's used in the banking system. It's one of those systems that you just wouldn't notice until something went wrong. </p>


<p>Earlier today, I tried depositing a check from a company only to have the the teller inform me that it couldn't be deposited today. When I asked why, she told me it was due to the fact that it wasn't in the system. Once I got home and looked up the number for the company, I called them, explained the situation, and they simply retransmitted the check details. </p>


<p>Since I helped build an ACH processing solution, I was curious about what this system entailed. Descriptions from several locations appeared using this <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=positive+pay" target="_blank">Google search</a>. One of the better descriptions was from <a href="http://www.positivepay.net/index.htm" target="_blank">SafeChecks</a>. Here is an excerpt.</p>


<blockquote><p>
Positive Pay is an automated fraud detection tool offered by the Cash Management Department of most banks. In its simplest form, it is a service that matches the <b>account number</b>, <b>check number</b> and <b>dollar</b> amount of each check presented for payment against a list of checks previously authorized and issued by the company. All three components of the check must match exactly or it will not pay.
</p></blockquote>


<p>The purpose of this system is to help prevent check fraud and the simplicity of it is encouraging. I can only hope that during transmittal they take the time to digitally sign the transactions.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
