<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Me | Meandering Out Loud]]></title>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/categories/me/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T18:57:07-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://donthorp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Don Thorp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meme: Six Random Facts About Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/10/21/meme-six-random-facts-about-me/"/>
    <updated>2008-10-21T16:44:44-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/10/21/meme-six-random-facts-about-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So my Twitter bud <a href="http://babblingaboutnothing.com/" target="_blank">Matt</a> aka <a href="http://twitter.com/mmWine" target="_blank">mmWine</a>, using his best evil laugh, <a href="http://babblingaboutnothing.com/?p=83" target="_blank">meme tagged</a> me for "Six Random Facts About Me". Looking around the Net I see that this meme has been running around for a while and has stayed basically true to form. The main deviation is changing the number of <b>random facts</b>. Since I wanted to be able to get some sleep tonight, I'm very thankful that Matt is passing on the six facts meme and not the 8 facts meme.</p>


<h2>Random Facts</h2>


<p>Let's consult "The Book of Don". </p>


<h3>Random Fact #1</h3>


<p>As a kid, I usually minded pretty well, but in this case I "bent" the rules a bit. We lived on a ranch in Missouri that had several ponds. One day as I was heading out for some reason mom told me to not get wet. Not sure how she knew I was considering going swimming in the pond, but she must have had an idea. But, I really wanted to see what it was like to swim in early April after the ice had thawed. Solution: Skinny dippin and  for the record it was cold, not too bad, but it also gave me the ability to sympathize with <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Costanza" target="_blank">George Constanza</a> years later. Oh and I returned home safe and dry.</p>


<h3>Random Fact #2</h3>


<p>Growing up on a ranch you also need certain skills, one of which is artificially breeding cattle. It's one of those skills that I don't think one can ever forget.</p>


<h3>Random Fact #3</h3>


<p>Laura and I got engaged after our third date. She lived in Amarillo at the time and I was still going to school at TCU. She had graduated a little earlier from TCU. Neither of us knew the other while we were at TCU. So three dates in less than a month and we're engaged. I can still remember us telling her parents as we were putting up the Christmas tree. First words out of her father's mouth ... "Are you pregnant". </p>


<p>It's worked out pretty well, we just had our 21st anniversary.</p>


<h3>Random Fact #4</h3>


<p>I've worked on many different projects over the years but three consumer items that I worked on were.</p>


<ol>
<li><a href="http://store.vintagepaperads.com/servlet/-strse-8908/1993-Tandy-Sensation-Computer/Detail" target="_blank">Tandy Sensation</a> the first Windows multimedia PC. Some one even put up a video of an <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h3U7DFUqoVM&feature=related" target="_blank">old commercial</a></li>
<li><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tandy_Video_Information_System" target="_blank">Tandy VIS</a> a horribly flawed device that we actually made sort of work, but it failed miserably.</li>
<li><a href="http://www.pcworld.com/article/126692-3/the_25_greatest_pcs_of_all_time.html" target="_blank">Gateway Destination PC</a> item #20 towards the bottom of the page. First real attempt to have a converged device in the Den.
</ol>


<h3>Random Fact #5</h3>


<p>I've been growing my hair out for over 18 months. The story of which will appear in an upcoming blog post. In the spirit of baring oneself, most of the hair is on the sides and back; Not so much contributed from the top of my scalp.</p>


<h3>Random Fact #6</h3>


<p>Self-funded (read really similar to starving college days) Select Payment Processing, with some friends. It was successfully sold years later.</p>


<h2>Tag You're It</h2>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/jmthorp" target="_blank">@jmthorp</a> who is my brother and writes <a href="http://thorplife.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">http://thorplife.wordpress.com/</a> after the kids crashed the hard drive on his old site.</p>


<p>John Munsch who has no twitter account, a long time friend,  and writes <a href="http://www.johnmunsch.com/" target="_blank">http://www.johnmunsch.com/</a></p>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/frizzle_fry" target="_blank">@frizzle_fry</a> Melissa Astle <del datetime="2008-10-22T19:53:58+00:00">who also has no twitter account,</del> whom I've worked with for years, never met, and writes <a href="http://randommisfires.wordpress.com" target="_blank">http://randommisfires.wordpress.com</a></p>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/dogwood" target="_blank">@dogwood</a> who writes <a href="http://thedogwoodreport.blogspot.com/" target="_blank">http://thedogwoodreport.blogspot.com/</a></p>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/stevesaylor" target="_blank">@stevesaylor</a> who writes <a href="http://stevesaylor.net/" target="_blank">http://stevesaylor.net/</a></p>


<p><a href="http://twitter.com/pprlisa" target="_blank">@pprlisa</a> who never writes but should at <a href="http://lemloo.wordpress.com/" target="_blank">http://lemloo.wordpress.com/</a></p>


<h2>The Rules</h2>


<p>The rules to play are easy …<br />
1. Link to the person who tagged you. <a href="http://babblingaboutnothing.com/?p=83" target="_blank">Matt Tagged me here</a>.<br />
2. Post the rules on the blog.<br />
3. Write six random things about yourself.<br />
4. Tag six people at the end of your post.<br />
5. Let each person know they have been tagged.<br />
6. Let the tagger know when your entry is up.</p>


<p>I look forward to learning about y’all. Tag, you’re it!</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2336 Days]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/08/08/2336-days/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-08T03:08:59-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/08/08/2336-days</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Goodbye</h3>


<p>Today is a day of transition from the known to the unknown. Last week I decided that I needed to take a break for a much needed rest. Two thousand three hundred thirty-five days ago on March 18, 2002, I said hello as employee number 18; Today on August 8, 2008 I say farewell. A thank you and best wishes to each and every one of the talented people I had the opportunity to travel with on that part of my journey. </p>


<h3>Inflection Points</h3>


<p>Every so often in my life an inflection point appears and when it does, I've learned to embrace it as a doorway to a new adventure. They're not always joyous adventures, but like any good adventure they provide tales for telling. These tales fit me well at this stage of my life. There are several transitions that I might detail in the future, but I want to touch on several of them in this story.</p>


<p>I can remember the first real transition and it's not a pleasant one. My dad passed away from cancer when I was 13 and a short while later mom told me that we'd have to move into town. I can remember clearly that my response was extreme frustration. I had lost dad and now I was losing access to all of the activities I loved: hunting, fishing, horseback riding, and even my chores. In a fury, I packed up all of my favorite items to get them out of my sight because I knew the enjoyable part of my life was done. It didn't take long for me to come to terms with the transition and once I did, I embraced it.</p>


<p>I had a couple of education related inflection points. During Spring Break of my Junior year of High School, I visited my grandparents who were wintering in South Texas. I'm fuzzy on the exact timing, I can't remember if I decided before or after break, but I knew when I returned that there was nothing left for me in High School. When I got home, I took the GED and started summer school at ORU where my step-dad was a professor. </p>


<p>I started off pre-med, the decided on pure Chemistry. I was enjoying the studies, but apparently I had approached another inflection point. I was standing in a lab three years later, having completed all of my Chemistry degree courses and one of my professors made a simple comment, "you are really good with computers, have you taken any courses?" Apparently that was the click of another door opening.</p>


<p>I had started programming on the TRS-80 model I when I was 13 or 14 and spent a large portion of my free time working with computers, but I had never really considered it as a profession. Shortly after the comment, I realized that while I liked Chemistry, I loved working with computers and the variety they presented. Before the end of the semester I started the transfer process to TCU and as soon as the semester ended, moved to Fort Worth, TX. I hadn't even been accepted yet, but I knew that's where I would be.</p>


<p>Near the end of my penultimate semester at TCU, Laura and I got engaged. Some of you are thinking OK, So? What you may not know is that we had only had 3 dates before the engagement. This transition was a little drawn out, but I graduated in May of 1987, started my first full time job in June of 1987, and got married on July 4th, 1987. For those of you trying to do the math, we've been married 21 years now. It may seem odd, but I knew that it was the correct door to step through. </p>


<p>Near the end of the .COM bubble, one of my good friends Bill and I decided to form a company. We had been contracting together doing software for the Destination PC and decided that we should open an office, which is a pretty big commitment. After a while, we decided to self-fund an idea and brought in another one of my good friends, John. John and I continued contracting to pay the bills and help part time on the project while Bill worked full time on the project. The story is too long to tell in full, but the short version is, John and I threw ourselves into the collapsing job market so that Bill could stay with Select Payment Processing to guide it through several tough years to a successful acquisition. If all three of us had stayed, the company would not have been able to survive the collapse of the bubble. That acquisition is helping allow me to discover my next adventure.</p>


<h3>The Unknown or There's a World Outside of Yonkers</h3>


<p><code>[kml_flashembed movie="http://www.youtube.com/v/WbBnXryfjg4" width="425" height="350" wmode="transparent" /]</code></p>


<p><br/><br />
This inflection point is a little different than the others in that I have nothing planned except rest. "Out There", from Hello Dolly, has been on an endless playback loop in my head the last couple of weeks. I think it helps convey the hope that this change presents. Next week is a little busy, we're going to have a HUGE garage sale, but I see that as part of the resting process. </p>


<p>My current short bio says "Overcommited, Developer, Entrepreneur, Part Time Trader". My new short bio? "Adventurer in Waiting". If you need to find me, look for a vista surveying a landscape of opportunity. Some where, out there, is the next doorway to adventure, I'm not sure where it is, but it's there. </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CREDANT Gets More Money]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/02/03/credant-gets-more-money/"/>
    <updated>2008-02-03T13:07:03-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/02/03/credant-gets-more-money</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've worked at my &quot;day job&quot;, <a href="http://www.credant.com" target"_blank">CREDANT Technologies, Inc</a>, for almost six years now. I happened to run across an article in the <a href="http://www.bizjournals.com/dallas/" target="_blank">Dallas Business Journal</a> and found out that <a href="http://www.bizjournals.com/dallas/stories/2008/01/28/newscolumn4.html?b=1201496400^1581658" target="_blank">Credant investors ante up $5M in 'top-off' funding round</a>. Not completely surprised, but I definitely wasn't expecting it.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Clutter of It All]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/01/27/the-clutter-of-it-all/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-27T08:04:20-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/01/27/the-clutter-of-it-all</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I find the affect of clutter to be cyclical. Sometimes, when I know what I need to get done and I can be fully absorbed in the task, it has no affect. Other times, when I don't have a clear picture on what needs to be done, it really bothers me.</p>


<p>There are a ton of tasks to be done this time every year: taxes, new development projects, school activities, etc. All of them seem to slowly suck the life out of me. Oh, and don't forget winter is starting to lose it's grasp, so yard work is about to start calling too. It's enough to make you want to crawl back in bed and pull the covers up. </p>


<p>I wonder if hibernation would get us out of doing taxes and  bookwork?</p>


<p>On the bright side, today was the first day of the year that it's nice enough to put the top down on the car and let the sunshine help drive the winter blues away. Maybe a few more days of direct sunlight will allow the winter fog to lift and release the energy that I need to start knocking tasks off the list.</p>


<p>Update: Reading through my news feed I ran across this post <a href="http://zenhabits.net/2008/01/a-guide-to-cutting-back-when-you-feel-overwhelmed/" target="_blank">A Guide to Cutting Back When You Feel Overwhelmed</a> from <a href="http://zenhabits.net/" target="_blank">Zen Habits</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello Thorp, Wisconsin!]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/01/12/hello-thorp-wisconsin/"/>
    <updated>2008-01-12T13:18:08-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/01/12/hello-thorp-wisconsin</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="float:right; margin-left: 15px; "><iframe width="250" height="200" frameborder="0" scrolling="no" marginheight="0" marginwidth="0" src="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;time=&amp;date=&amp;ttype=&amp;q=thorp,+wi&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;om=1&amp;s=AARTsJpy2zHH1FXH_G28kBa5BOcfD3YwFQ&amp;ll=44.958846,-90.798912&amp;spn=0.024294,0.042915&amp;z=13&amp;output=embed"></iframe><br /><small><a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;time=&amp;date=&amp;ttype=&amp;q=thorp,+wi&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;om=1&amp;ll=44.958846,-90.798912&amp;spn=0.024294,0.042915&amp;z=13&amp;source=embed" style="color:#0000FF;text-align:left">View Larger Map</a></small></div>


<p>Imagine my surprise when a slip of a google search turns up a town with my surname, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thorp,_Wisconsin" target="_blank">Thorp, Wisconsin</a>. My earlier years were spent in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sarcoxie%2C_Missouri" target="_blank">Sarcoxie, Missouri</a> (pop 1280, back then). The population of Thorp is 1536, from the last census numbers. I'm guessing with a well timed Google street view, you might be able to see everyone in town.</p>


<p>Visiting the cities' website (<a href="http://www.cityofthorp.com/" target="_blank">http://www.cityofthorp.com/</a>) it looks to be a nice place with lots of civic activities and nice public facilities. Here is a brief <a href="http://www.cityofthorp.com/cityofthorp/history+of+thorp/default.asp" target="_blank">history</a> of the town which was founded in 1893.</p>


<p>Thanks <a href="http://www.google.com">Google</a> for bringing me some fun information.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
