<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Home | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/categories/home/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T18:27:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://donthorp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Projects: Bedroom Remodel]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/20/projects-bedroom-remodel/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-20T17:49:10-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2009/01/20/projects-bedroom-remodel</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/gallery/7149761_axaYq" class="noicon" target="_blank" style="float: right; padding-left:10px; padding-bottom: 10px;"><img src="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/photos/458754492_kbWud-S.jpg" border="no"/></a> I've create a <a href="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/gallery/7149761_axaYq" target="_blank">gallery</a> of photos from the remodel of Allison's bedroom. She wanted her walls red with a dark wood floor. Given the experience we had with renovating my office in 2008, we were confident we could crank out most of the work over the MLK holiday weekend. As of this post we've completed everything except the baseboard and moving her in.</p>


<p>We ripped out the 13+ year old carpet and replaced it with a floating bamboo floor. The walls were painted with a dark brown (Behr Bison Brown) and then covered the brown with red (Behr Daredevil). The eggshell finish for the red gives it a glazed look and provides for an interesting finish over the brown. The original baseboard was repainted and replaced and shoe molding will be added to cover any gaps from contraction.</p>


<p>I hope to post a howto in the future, now that we've installed two floating floors using this bamboo flooring, </p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It Was a Slow Draining Day]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/09/11/it-was-a-slow-draining-day/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-11T09:31:15-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/09/11/it-was-a-slow-draining-day</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/09/drano.jpg" alt="Picture of a Drano bottle" title="drano" width="74" height="137" class="alignleft size-full wp-image-105" />The shower has been draining slowly for a few days. On her way to work this morning, Laura called to remind me to pour <a href="http://www.drano.com/plumbing-problems/default.aspx" target="_blank">Drano</a> down the shower drain. Having a little extra energy this morning, I decided to go the extra mile and see if I could clean it by hand before using chemicals. That way, the Drano would be much more effective and have much less work to do. </p>


<div style="float:right; text-align:center;"><a href="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/gallery/5945484_tW2py/1/#370535792_DRix7-A-LB" target="_blank"><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/09/tab.jpg" alt="Tab on Drain Cover" title="tab" width="117" height="100" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-106" align="center" style='padding-left: 10px' /></a><br/><a href="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/gallery/5945484_tW2py/1/#370535792_DRix7-A-LB" target="_blank">Click for Larger Image</a></div>


<p>I've wondered for years how the drain cover stays in place, but I never bothered to actually look. On close inspection there seemed to be four tabs holding it in place, so a little pressure and it popped right out. If you look closely, you'll see a little bump on the tab that helps keep it below the rim.</p>


<p>After successfully pulling the cover off, I peered into the drain and was greeted by a glob of stuff that honestly, was probably alive. Reaching in the drain, I SLOWLY pulled and pulled and pulled, until finally with a soft plop, an ENTIRE ponytail looking creature was resting peacefully on the shower floor. Thankfully, it didn't spring to life and attack.</p>


<p style="width:75%; margin-left: 12%; border: solid 1px black; background-color: #FFFFCC; padding: 5px;"><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/09/warning-20x20.png" alt="" title="warning-20x20" width="25" height="25" class="size-full wp-image-107" style='float:left;' />For the squeamish among you, I won't embed the pictures, but for the rest of you crazy people, head over to my SmugMug Gallery <a href="http://donthorp.smugmug.com/gallery/5945484_tW2py#370498141_opqNF" target="_blank">Drain Life</a>.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
