<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Parenthood | Meandering Out Loud]]></title>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/categories/parenthood/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-21T19:37:05-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://donthorp.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Don Thorp]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Alex Goes to Washington]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/08/16/alex-goes-to-washington/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-16T14:05:51-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/08/16/alex-goes-to-washington</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://photos.donthorp.net/photos/280958496_gfqL8-S.jpg" width="200" height="150" style="float:right" />Off and on all summer, we've been trying to figure out how to get Alex to school. He is attending <a href="http://www.american.edu/index1.html" target="_blank">The American University</a> in Washington, DC and will be majoring in <a href="http://www.american.edu/sis/" target="_blank">International Studies</a>. </p>


<p>We had several options:</p>


<ol>
<li>Drive and tour the eastern part of the US</li>
<li>Drive one-way and fly home</li>
<li>Have the Family fly out carrying some of his bags and have a mini-vacation in DC
<li>Put Alex on the plane and say have fun</li>
</ol>


<p>The last option may seem a little harsh for sending your child off to college, but we've had a couple of years to prepare. Alex attended the <a href="http://www.tams.unt.edu/" target="_blank">Texas Academy of Mathematics and Science (TAMS)</a> at the University of North Texas for his last two years of High School. The program is a residence program where kids can take college courses and earn their High School degree. This period allowed all of us to adjust to him being away from home, but not so far that we couldn't meet up on a whim.</p>


<p><img src='http://amthorp.smugmug.com/photos/315244516_ZNeM4-S.jpg' width='112' height='150' style="float:left"/>Soon after he graduated, we put him on a plane for summer school in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guadalajara,_Jalisco" target="_blank">Guadalajara, Jalisco Mexico</a> at the <a href="http://www.cepe.udg.mx/" target="_blank">Universidad de Guadalajara CEPE</a>. He took a couple of courses and was able to tour the region where he took many interesting <a href="http://amthorp.smugmug.com/Mexico" target="_blank">photos</a>. All of Alex's photos are available on his <a href="http://amthorp.smugmug.com/" target="_blank">SmugMug account</a>. He may have visited other places, but I do know he went to Puerto Vallarta, Guanajuato, and Zapopan a suburb of Guadalajara. One of the messages from him during the trip informed us that Guanajuato would be a great place for us to live if we ever do decide to retire in Mexico.</p>


<p>After he came back from Mexico, he hung out with us for a while before taking a driving tour of the Western US. I have yet to go through all of the <a href="http://amthorp.smugmug.com/Road%20Trip%2008" target="_blank">photos of 'Road Trip 08'</a>, but it looks like they had a great time. The trip started in Jackson Hole, WY where his friend Laura picked him up from the airport and ended in Corpus Christi, TX at Laura's house.</p>


<p>Alex came back in time to get off the bus from Corpus to help us load a U-Haul trailer full of stuff to transport to Tulsa where we exchanged it for other stuff, to bring back to Texas. I found out that he'd had maybe one hour of sleep since leaving Corpus after he learned of the Canadian bus incident; after the trip had started. He helped us prepare for the garage sale before packing his things for school. He had whittled things down before he left for Mexico, but he was able to make another pass through to provide more fodder for the sale.</p>


<p>I've been telling a good friend of mine for weeks, that we were probably going to just send Alex to school because he didn't have enough stuff for us to need to drive. Here's the proof.</p>


<p>His total belongings amounted to:</p>


<ol>
<li>3 boxes shipped via UPS ($88 ground, 2 day air was $425, um no thanks)</li>
<li>backpack (not shown)</li>
<li>2 bags with him on the plane ($40 in excess baggage fees)</li>
</ol>


<p>Sorry for the poor images (silly camera on phone), but I think it shows that it really was minimal.</p>


<table>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/08/luggage02.jpg" alt="Boxes at Fedex" title="luggage02" width="300" height="225" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-100" /></td>
<td><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/08/luggage01.jpg" alt="Bags carried with him." title="luggage01" width="300" height="225" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-99" />
</td>
</tr>
</table>


<p>So this morning at 5:30 AM, Alex and I headed to Dallas-Fort Worth International Airport so that he could catch his 7:20 AM plane to DC. We walked in, I paid for the extra baggage, $40, gave him a hug and headed back to open the garage sale.</p>


<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/08/flight-info.png" alt="" title="flight-info" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-101" /></p>


<p>When I got home, I realized he had forgotten the tracking information for the boxes. So I typed them up and shipped him a quick email. Then to let me know when they arrived, I added them to <a href="http://trackthis.pb30.com/" target="_blank">TrackThis</a> so that I would be notified on <a href="http://twitter.com/donthorp" target="_blank">my Twitter account</a> when the packages arrived.</p>


<table width="99%">
<tr>
<td align='center'><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/08/trackit.png" alt="TrackThis items." title="trackit" width="291" height="195" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-102" /></td>
</tr>
</table>


<p><p>A few hours later, at approximately 10:00 AM CDT, I sent this tweet.<br />
<table width="99%">
<tr>
<td align="center"><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/08/picture-1.png" alt="" title="picture-1" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-103" /></td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>At 10:10 AM CDT, I received this text from Alex</p>
<blockquote><p>
Just touched down
</p></blockquote>
<p>At 11:36 AM CDT, he announced his arrival at his room, which he&rsquo;s sharing with two others.</p>
<blockquote><p>
&hellip;only two desks.
</p></blockquote>
<p>At 1:46 PM CDT, I knew everything was ok, because I was informed I owed him money.</p>
<blockquote><p>
School supplies were 50 &hellip; showers are good..better than our house
</p></blockquote>
<p>At 1:53 PM CDT, I received an email, that told me that he was settled in and rarin to go.</p>
<blockquote><p>
 &hellip; edited &hellip;<br />
 Now I&rsquo;m off to look into getting my iphone (:
</p></blockquote>
<p>Hopefully soon, I&rsquo;ll get the text or phone call from said iPhone to prove that everything turned out as expected. Otherwise, he&rsquo;ll need money at some point, then I&rsquo;ll hear from him.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Parent 23,290 - Teenager 0]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/04/23/parent-23290-teenager-0/"/>
    <updated>2008-04-23T12:22:29-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/04/23/parent-23290-teenager-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have to admit, I was part of the problem, but it is very hard to resist coming to the aid of another parent when challenged by a teenager. I woke up this morning and saw this tweet which I've edited to remove the actual phone number.</p>


<blockquote><p>
<span style="color:blue">T+0h</span> <a href="http://twitter.com/leolaporte" target="_blank">leolaporte</a> My son Hank doesn't believe I have so many followers. He says text him if you follow me here. 707 XXX-YYYY. Let's see how many msgs he gets.
</p></blockquote>


<p>Not long after, this tweet appeared.</p>


<blockquote><p>
<span style="color:blue">T+0h</span> <a href="http://twitter.com/leolaporte" target="_blank">leolaporte</a>  OK that was a really bad idea. ;-)
</p></blockquote>


<p>I woke up in this period and couldn't help but send my own text message to poor Hank. Telling him in fact that I did follow his dad on twitter. </p>


<p>Several hours later.</p>


<blockquote><p>
<span style="color:blue">T+10h</span> <a href="http://twitter.com/leolaporte" target="_blank">leolaporte</a> Boy it sure is hard deleting old tweets. Pownce and Jaiku delete them right away. Guess Hank's phone will be unusable today.
</p></blockquote>


<p>The damage assessment will come.</p>


<blockquote><p>
<span style="color:blue">T+11h</span> <a href="http://twitter.com/leolaporte" target="_blank">leolaporte</a> I won't know the total number of text messages Hank received until I get the bill, but it was in the thousands. He had to turn off the phone
</p></blockquote>


<p>And finally,</p>


<blockquote><p>
<span style="color:blue">T+11h</span> <a href="http://twitter.com/leolaporte" target="_blank">leolaporte</a> I DDoSed my own son.
</p></blockquote>


<p>While it may be a little extreme you can't help but cheer just a little. How many times are parents challenged with no real way to prove a child wrong. Will it prevent Hank from challenging Dad in the future, probably not, he is a teenager after all. Will it make him think twice, just maybe.</p>


<p>Oh and the score in the title, the number of <a href="http://twitter.com">Twitter</a> users following Leo that had the opportunity to send a nice encouraging text to Hank.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Say Bridge]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/03/15/say-bridge/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-15T07:29:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/03/15/say-bridge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Children are the spice of life. </p>


<p>While attending my youngest sister's baby shower in Tulsa, Allison was able to capture this priceless video of my nephew trying to say "bridge".</p>


<p><code>[kml_flashembed movie="http://www.youtube.com/v/r4sbky11P14" width="425" height="350" wmode="transparent" /]</code></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Spongebob Probe]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/03/05/the-sponge-bob-probe/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-05T16:49:51-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/03/05/the-sponge-bob-probe</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img style="float:right" src="http://boingboing.net/images/spongebobrectal1.jpg" /> It's hard to imagine anyone approving this product, but then again, it happened. How many children are going to scream at the site of Sponge Bob in the future. To help complete the traumatization of America, they should also release a Krusty the Clown probe as well. </p>


<p><a href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/boingboing/iBag/~3/240192974/spongebob-squarepant.html" target="_blank">Found on Boing Boing</a></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Spoon Death Aka "Solutions From the Teenage Mind"]]></title>
    <link href="http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/03/02/spoon-death-aka-solutions-from-the-teenage-mind/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-02T08:46:32-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://donthorp.github.io/blog/2008/03/02/spoon-death-aka-solutions-from-the-teenage-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/05/spoons.jpg" alt="Pile of mangled spoons" title="spoons" width="250" height="211" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-82" style="float:right" /> Authors on the Net don't always consider their readership. For instance, consider the problem of puffy eyes or bags under the eyes. In the modern world what do we do? Google of course. Who is allowed to use Google? Everyone, including teenagers.</p>


<p>Take a moment to read the following excerpt found during my quest to answer the question, "What the hell was she thinking?".</p>


<blockquote><p>
Here are some instructions to reduce eye puffiness: </p>
<p>The puffiness of the eyes can be reduced with a glass of ice water and<br />
four stainless steel spoons.</p>
<p>“Chill the spoons in the water and then place one over each eye. When<br />
the spoons become warm, switch them with the others chilling in the<br />
glass of water. Keep switching until you see improvement.” </p>
<p><a href="http://answers.google.com/answers/threadview?id=188839" target="_blank">Link</a>
</p></blockquote>


<p>Obviously, the author didn't consider the improvisation and lack of forethought that is the hallmark of a teenage mind. For example the following questions should have probably been asked.</p>


<ul>
<li>What is an alternative place to cool spoons?</li>
<li>Does a teenager always remember that they started something?</li>
<li>Does a teenager think, is this a good idea?</li>
</ul>


<p>For instance, why bother with a glass out of the cabinet, filling it with ice, water, and worry about wet spoons, when you can simply drop them in the ice maker? </p>


<p>What could go wrong, it's not moving now, how could the spoons cause a problem? </p>


<p>Imagine the dialog.</p>


<ul>
<li><b>Parent:</b> Honey, how long have the spoons been in the ice maker? </li>
<li><b>Teenager:</b> Ice maker? Who would put spoons in the ice maker? </li>
</ul>


<p>The funny thing is, the ice maker functioned for a very long time with spoons wrapped around in various places. Just as surprising is that an ice maker has enough torque to bend spoons and not just jam. </p>


<p>I discovered this "experiment" yesterday when we replaced our aging refrigerator with a one year old unit we bought from a friend. I took the ice bin outside and dumped it in the flower bed and was a little startled when I heard metallic clinking as the ice hit the ground.</p>


<p>So, to all your helpful Heloise's out there, please consider that teenagers do roam the Net and their solution may just surprise you.</p>


<table width="80%">
<tr>
<td><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/05/img_6157.jpg" alt="" title="img_6157" width="200" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-83" /></td>
<td><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/05/img_6158.jpg" alt="" title="img_6158" width="200" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-84" /></td>
<td><img src="http://donthorp.github.io/content/uploads/2008/05/img_6166.jpg" alt="" title="img_6166" width="200" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-85" /></td>
</tr>
</table>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
